<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>Snoop Snoo Blog</title>
        <description>Snoop Snoo Blog - OrionMelt</description>
        <link>blog.snoopsnoo.com</link>
        <link>blog.snoopsnoo.com</link>
        <lastBuildDate>2015-01-14T22:27:23-07:00</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>2015-01-14T22:27:23-07:00</pubDate>
        <ttl>1800</ttl>


        <item>
                <title>What's better than version 0.1?</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;Version 0.2, of course. Since the public release of &lt;span class=&quot;logo logo-small&quot;&gt;SNOOP &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/themes/snoopsnoo/img/logo_sm.png&quot; /&gt; SNOO&lt;/span&gt; ten days ago, I’ve received lots of feedback that helped me make some important changes. I’ve just published v0.2 of the site, and I hope to continue to add features and improve accuracy. Here is the list of new features that went live today:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can now refresh data to keep your profile up-to-date.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Client-side fetching of data to prevent “Server too busy” errors.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;See which subreddits are most likely to bring you maximum karma.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Charts detailing last 60 days of activity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All charts updated to use local timezone instead of UTC.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Help categorize your subreddits.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marginally improved NLP.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bug fixes and cosmetic changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the new features? Hate the changes? Want a new feature altogether? Let me know in the comments below, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=orionmelt&quot;&gt;PM me on reddit&lt;/a&gt; or head over to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/SnoopSnoo&quot;&gt;/r/SnoopSnoo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>blog.snoopsnoo.com/2015/01/10/whats-better-than-version-01</link>
                <guid>blog.snoopsnoo.com/2015/01/10/whats-better-than-version-01</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-01-10T00:00:00-07:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Hello reddit.</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;I had wanted to add several new features to &lt;span class=&quot;logo logo-small&quot;&gt;SNOOP &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/themes/snoopsnoo/img/logo_sm.png&quot; /&gt; SNOO&lt;/span&gt; before I released it publicly, such as letting users authenticate via OAuth, profile views and even more charts and analytics. But after realizing that it would never be &lt;em&gt;truly&lt;/em&gt; ready for public release, I bought SnoopSnoo.com, uploaded the current version and posted the link on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/InternetIsBeautiful/comments/2qucap/a_website_that_shows_interesting_information/&quot;&gt;/r/InternetIsBeautiful&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/dataisbeautiful/comments/2r3jnk/your_reddit_activity_analyzed_and_visualized_oc/&quot;&gt;/r/dataisbeautiful&lt;/a&gt;. Both posts were received quite well, and I got a ton of useful feedback from redditors. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone suggested that I crosspost it to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/secretsanta/comments/2r7xhr/website_that_shows_interesting_information_about/&quot;&gt;/r/secretsanta&lt;/a&gt; - I did and the response was excitingly positive. I hadn’t even considered this use case, so it was great to discover new ways people could use the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, on to actually making use of the feedback I received and make some changes!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>blog.snoopsnoo.com/2015/01/05/hello-reddit</link>
                <guid>blog.snoopsnoo.com/2015/01/05/hello-reddit</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-01-05T00:00:00-07:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Let's begin.</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;Hello, and welcome to &lt;span class=&quot;logo logo-small&quot;&gt;SNOOP &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/themes/snoopsnoo/img/logo_sm.png&quot; /&gt; SNOO&lt;/span&gt;’s development blog. I’ve been on reddit since its inception way back in 2005 (mostly lurking, though) and have always thought it would be interesting to analyze the massive amounts of data it generates, especially after its huge growth in the past few years – so I built &lt;span class=&quot;logo logo-small&quot;&gt;SNOOP &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/themes/snoopsnoo/img/logo_sm.png&quot; /&gt; SNOO&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of today, it simply does two things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aggregate your reddit submissions and comments, and graphically display resulting data.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Parse text in your comments and submissions, and extract relevant and potentially interesting information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I built the web app in about three weeks, but I’ve been working on its NLP components for a couple of months now. I’m still new to NLP and as I try to wrap my head around it, results may often be erratic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site is built on &lt;a href=&quot;http://flask.pocoo.org/&quot;&gt;Flask&lt;/a&gt; and hosted on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/&quot;&gt;Google Cloud Platform&lt;/a&gt;. Charts are generated using &lt;a href=&quot;http://d3js.org/&quot;&gt;D3.js&lt;/a&gt;. The NLP component is built on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sloria/TextBlob&quot;&gt;TextBlob&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nltk.org/&quot;&gt;NLTK&lt;/a&gt;, and is hosted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blockspring.com/&quot;&gt;Blockspring&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to update this blog regularly as the site evolves. Really. I’ve even made a New Year’s resolution and everything.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>blog.snoopsnoo.com/2015/01/01/lets-begin</link>
                <guid>blog.snoopsnoo.com/2015/01/01/lets-begin</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-01-01T00:00:00-07:00</pubDate>
        </item>


</channel>
</rss>
